

JOSEPH RIPAMONTI

https://josephripamonti.com/

ABOUT ME

Digital marketer with a background in social media, e-commerce, and business entrepreneurship. With a record gained from my experience and the current development of my own brand, I'm ready to leverage my comprehensive skill set to drive success in the digital landscape.

CONTACT

joseph.ripamonti@gmail.com <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-ripamonti/</u> Whatsapp: +39 3420975007 Phone: +39 3513497594

LANGUAGES

Italian - Native

English - Full Professional Proficiency

Spanish - Professional Proficiency

French - Beginner Level (A1)

CORE SKILLS

Social Media
Time Management
Marketing & Branding
E-commerce
Copywriting

INTERESTS

Nutrition Sport Health & Wellness Fashion Travel

WORK EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER

Notimize

July 2023 - Present

Notimize offers Notion Templates that help people get organized, productive, and achieve their goals.

It's allowing me to dive into all the different tasks of online selling and digital marketing.

- Checked out how well the business could do by studying the market and the competitors
- Creating the website using Webflow
- Planning an effective marketing strategy and a social media content calendar to drive brand visibility and engagement
- Implementing automations using Zapier
- Creating Notion Templates to enhance productivity and organization
- Writing compelling copy for diverse platforms including websites, product listings, and social media channels, ensuring consistent and impactful brand messaging

AFFILIATE MARKETING MANAGER & SOCIAL MEDIA

The Value Factory SL (Barcelona, Spain) Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

- Create the right communication strategy to improve conversions and strengthen the client's brand through the identification of the right partners
- Successfully manage and develop several markets worldwide
- Improve the online brand image of the agency through a LinkedIn b2b organic content strategy (+51% followers)
- Improve the online coverage of the company by contacting blogs and website owners
- Prospect and sign 10+ new partners

FREELANCE TRANSLATOR

Kilo.Health (Vilnius, Lithuania) Dec 2019 - Present

- Effective localization of digital content (e-commerce, apps, websites, advertorials)
- Transcription of advertising videos
- Translation of advertorials taking care of SEO and copywriting for the Italian market

EDUCATION N

START2IMPACT

Ecommerce Branding & Strategy (2022 - Present)

UNIVERSITY MILANO-BICOCCA

B.sc. in Marketing, Business Communication and Global Markets (2018 - 2021)

KAZIMIERAS SIMONAVICIUS UNIVERSITY

Erasmus+ 2019/20

One academic year in Vilnius, Lithuania